hey everyone welcome back to this task
automation playlist and we are going to
continue talking about different string
operations which are present in Tosca
now we have spoken about some of the
operations uh where we did a string
replace we use the trim function to
basically remove all the white space
characters and we use the string replace
to basically replace some part of the
string with some other uh pattern or
string right
we have also seen how we can use the
base64 string operation to encode and
decode our strings
and now we are going to talk about the
remaining four string operations and
these are the string to lower string to
Upper number of occurrences and string
length
now by the name you can think what a
string length will do it will basically
provide you the length of the string
right so it will count the number of
characters and it will return you the
length
the number of occurrences this is a
useful uh operation where you want to
count all the occurrences of a defined
input or pattern within a particular
string okay then string to Upper it
converts the lowercase characters to
upper case and string to lower it
converts the upper case to lower case
now this might seem very similar to you
if you have worked on any programming
language like Java you can perform all
of these operations uh directly in Java
right but here uh Tosca has already
given you uh different Expressions which
through which you can perform just
string operations this could be useful
uh especially uh when you're working in
Automation and you have to maybe format
or change particular strings then you
can use these different operations to
carry out those uh particular automation
okay
so let's quickly see how you can do this
okay so we will
remaining a string operations we will do
it here so string operations okay
for this I am going to use first a t-box
set buffer
and here I'm going to
create a buffer called Str and this will
contain something like placentis.com
okay
now
what we can do is uh
we can now have another buffer okay
where
um we will return the length of the
string
so here I'm going to use the buffer of
Str
UCT actually we need to first use the
string operation so we will use string
length and inside that we will use the
buffer okay
okay so I will close this
okay so this will return me the string
length Okay and we'll store it in a
buffer called length now if I want my
string uh to be converted into upper
case so let's create a buffer here
called uppercase and here again the same
way first we will do the string
operation so
type string to Upper
inside this we will then use the buffer
so we will use the buffer Str
ose the brackets
okay
and again for lowercase is the same
so lowercase I am going to just copy
this just to make it little faster
so I'm going to make it string to lower
and then the final one which is number
of occurrences right so I'm going to
name it number
and this time around we will be using
um not string but number of occurrences
you can see here
inside this now we will give uh
the actual string so which is B of Str
buffer
and then close this okay
also
we need to pass the string okay for
which we want the number of occurrences
or the pattern okay
so this will be your characters so which
characters do you want to uh find the
number of occurrences
uh let's say I want to find the number
of occurrences for
um t Okay so that's the character I want
to find the number of occurrences for
um and then
we can close this okay
so here um in the pattern okay it can be
one character it can be multiple
characters if you want to find the
complete licenses uh that also you can
do okay so it is very useful to find the
number of occurrences of any particular
pattern or character okay
so let's quickly go ahead and run this
and see if it is working as expected
okay so if I go into the logs now I
should be able to see my results so you
can see the length is 15 characters
uh it has converted into uppercase then
it is converted into lowercase
and then the buffer is set to one uh
which is actually correct
now you will ask me um there are
multiple T but if you look at it okay so
there are uppercase t and there is one
lowercase T and that is what it has
returned us now if you want all the t's
no matter if it is uppercase or
lowercase
then you need to pass an optional
parameter okay so here uh after uh the
pattern you also need to pass whether
you want uh to ignore the case while
finding the number of occurrences so
that you can do using this ignore case
parameter so this is an optional
parameter which I did not give it first
time okay but now I am providing it so
now the value should be 3 instead of
just one okay
so let's go ahead and run this
and if I check the number is 3 now okay
so no matter if it is uppercase or
lowercase it is going to find the number
of occurrences
so this way you can use all of these
different operations which are related
to string so you can use them at
different places of your automation
whenever you are trying to extract some
value from the application or you are
trying to compare some expected versus
actual results or you are trying to
modify your strengths right so there are
lots of operations uh which are required
when you are automating a particular
application and this could be a very
useful although it is very simple you
should be able to use them uh within
Tosca
so that's all about string operations I
hope you liked it and you learned
something new today if you like our
videos then do subscribe to our channel
uh we would be coming up with lots more
videos
so until we speak again keep learning
and keep watching our Channel